<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>CFA Exam Level 1</title>
        <description>CFA Exam Level 1 - Victor Sowers</description>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2015-08-05T21:40:16-04:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2015-08-05T21:40:16-04:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>There are no shortcuts</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;there-are-no-shortcuts-to-the-cfa-exam&quot;&gt;There are no shortcuts to the CFA Exam&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of the CFA Level 1 process may just be getting started. It’s also the most important part.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CFA material is long (2,500+ pages for level 1 alone). It is detailed. It will take time to learn the material, understand the types of problems you’ll need to know how to answer, and then practice over and over until you get comfortable.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s true even if you’ve worked in finance for 30 years. There are no real shortcuts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gospel is that the average Candidate needs to study 300 hours to pass the test. It could be more or less for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our job here at &lt;a href=&quot;www.cfaexamlevel1.com&quot;&gt;Go Study&lt;/a&gt; is to make sure you learn everything you need to pass the test while minimizing that time commitment.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all about quality and efficiency here (&lt;a href=&quot;www.cfaexamlevel3.com&quot;&gt;just ask the 500+ level 3 Candidates we just helped)&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, efficiency has limits. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-just-start-start-mentally-prepared&quot;&gt;Don’t just start, start mentally prepared&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passing all three Level 3 exams is a daunting challenge, and for your own sake you should be mentally prepared for that grind before you start Level 1. There are no prizes for being stuck as a CFA Level II Candidate.  You will make sacrifices with your time, there will be &lt;em&gt;opportunity costs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It will take years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still interested?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CFA curriculum will teach you something new. Its community is powerful, its designation recognized throughout the world. It can help open doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-will-help-you-walk-the-path&quot;&gt;We will help you walk the path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know the pain of passing these tests. We’ve been where you are.  We are here to help. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first step with us should be to register for our newsletter from our &lt;a href=&quot;www.cfaexamlevel1.com&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt;. It’s completely free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just like we did with level 3, we’ll use our newsletter to release  hundreds of pages of our Level 1 notes to you for free as well as sharing tips, tricks, additional study resources, walk throughs of difficult problems, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/blog/there-are-no-shortcuts</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/blog/there-are-no-shortcuts</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Coming soon.</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/blog/read-me</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/blog/read-me</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
