<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>CFA Exam Level 1</title>
        <description>CFA Exam Level 1 - Victor Sowers</description>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2015-10-24T13:46:38-04:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2015-10-24T13:46:38-04:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>What you need to know from the DCF Reading in L1 Quant Methods</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;here-are-the-5-most-likely-things-to-be-tested-from-l1s-discounted-cash-flow-readings&quot;&gt;Here are the 5 most-likely things to be tested from L1’s Discounted cash flow readings&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without further delay let’s break down the key themes from the discounted cash flow reading and how to apply them to answer likely exam questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solving-npv--irr-problems-using-your-financial-calculator-&quot;&gt;Solving NPV &amp;amp; IRR Problems Using your Financial Calculator **&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The basic framework to solving NPV problems, aka “what questions to ask”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. ID all the benefits (inflows) and costs (outflows)
2. Determine the right discount rate to use
3. Discount each cash flow using the discount rate. When inputting the cash flows, inflows are positive and outflows            are negative.
4. The NPV is the sum of each discounted cash flow (DCF)
5. Make a decision on the capital budget project (i.e. is NPV &amp;gt; 0?)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solving NPV on your financial calculator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To calculate NPV on your financial calculator you need to use the cash flow (CF) function.  Every time you do this on the exam make sure to clear all previous cash flows work by pressing ([CF][2nd][CLR WORK]. &lt;strong&gt;One big key to passing is not to lose points on problems you know the answer to!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re ready, start by entering all of the sequential cash flows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* CF0 is in the initial outlay and will be a negative number for a corporate finance project
* CF1 is the first period’s cash flow and so on and so forth. Remember to use net cash flows.
* When you are done entering the cash flows, hit NPV and enter the interest rate for I=?
* Key down and CPT the NPV
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solve for IRR using your financial calculator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps for entering cash flows are identical to NPV problems. The only difference is that we now hit [IRR][CPT] to calculate the IRR (and of course we are not asked to input an external interest rate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-able-to-comparecontrast-the-use-of-npv-and-irr-especially-when-dealing-with-mutually-exclusive-projects&quot;&gt;Be able to compare/contrast the use of NPV and IRR, especially when dealing with mutually exclusive projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a single project NPV and IRR will result in the same decision. Any project with a positive NPV will have an IRR &amp;gt; required rate of return and vice versa &lt;em&gt;(when NPV = 0, the IRR = the required rate of return).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when facing mutually exclusive projects, or projects with non-conventional cash flow patterns, NPV and IRR can give conflicting answers. This is a result of either different initial costs or uneven timing of cash flows. Just remember, the &lt;strong&gt;sooner&lt;/strong&gt; cash flows occur, the &lt;strong&gt;higher&lt;/strong&gt; an IRR will be &lt;strong&gt;even if the ultimate NPV of that project ends up being lower.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Summarizing NPV   and IRR&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Net Present Value&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Internal Rate of Return&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-Directly   measures increase in value of firm.    -Assumes CF   reinvested at opportunity cost of capital&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-Considers   TVM  and all CF   -Is less   subjective since doesn’t depend on external r   -Easy to   understand   -Widely accepted&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Limitations&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-Based on   external market-determined discount rate (r)   -Assumes r   stable over time&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-Assumes that   cash flows reinvested at IRR&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Decision Rule&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NPV &amp;gt; IRR for   mutually exclusive projects. For independent projects will give same answer   (IRR &amp;gt; opportunity cost of capital then NPV &amp;gt; 0 and vice versa.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Reasons for different rankings&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-Different cash   flow reinvestment rates and cash flow patterns   -Size (IRR Works   better with smaller opportunities)   -Timing of Cash   Flows – more CF in early years favors IRR&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calculating-twrr-and-comparing-it-against-mwrr&quot;&gt;Calculating TWRR, and comparing it against MWRR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the timing the timing of cash flows is different, MWRR and TWRR can give different returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Summarizing TWRR and MWRR&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TWRR&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MWRR&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Calculation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Each CF-free sub-period   is chained together&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Solve using your financial calculator&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Advantages&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Measures actual rate of return earned by manager   Not sensitive to external CFs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Only requires an account to be valued at beginning   and end&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Requires an account/portfolio value at time of each   cash flow   Can be expensive and time consuming to compute&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MWRR hugely impacted by external cash flows&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Appropriate When&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Portfolio manager does NOT have discretion over   deposits and withdrawals made by clients&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Portfolio manager has discretion over deposits and   withdrawals made by clients&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Performance differences&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;·           If   large CFs come in before strong   performance MWRR &amp;gt; TWRR   ·           If   those CFs come in before poor performance,   however, MWRR &amp;lt; TWRR.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;navigate-between-holding-period-return-bank-discount-yield-effective-annual-yield--money-market-yield-and-the-bond-equivalent-yield&quot;&gt;Navigate between Holding Period Return, Bank Discount Yield, Effective Annual Yield / Money Market Yield, and the bond equivalent yield&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be able to convert from one to the other and also know which yields the highest value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The HPY is the total return if the investor holds the note until maturity (coupon pmts, reinvestment return, final value)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The EAY is the annualized HPY which uses a 365 day/year (sometimes 360) and accounts for compounding. To get EAY from the total holding perior return: EAY = (HPY)^(1/n)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The BEY determines annualizes the yield of an investment that does not make annual payments. This allows investors to compare fixed-income securities whose payments are not annual or are selling at a discount to those with annual yields.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The BDY is the annualized yield based on simple interest and 360 days/year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Go Practice!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/blog/how-dcf-shows-up-on-l1</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/blog/how-dcf-shows-up-on-l1</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>A 3 Month Schedule for Passing the CFA Level 1 Exam</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;month-cfa-l1-game-plan&quot;&gt;3 Month CFA L1 Game Plan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s late September already and despite your best intentions you’ve barely made a dent in the CFA Level 1 material. Now you have thousands of pages of material left to read and only 15 weeks in which to cover everything AND have enough time to review and do mock exams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get it. If you are taking Level 1 in December your situation is far from ideal. But you’ve probably beat yourself up enough about not being far enough along in the process. We’re not here to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re here to present an ambitious but feasible schedule to get you through the material while doing enough practice problems and building in enough review to pass this test. &lt;em&gt;And if you’re taking the exam in June you can either space out our suggested order, or not study at all until March and read this then :).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the rest of the post we will&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Illustrate what we think “studying” or covering a session really means&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outline the schedule of readings to cover&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End by presenting some alternative methods to cram this material in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-it-mean-to-cover-the-material&quot;&gt;What does it mean to Cover the Material?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think there are some best practices for reviewing the study material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read our Summary Notes for the given chapter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the Curriculum or Detailed Third Party Notes. Spend more time on sections you’re weak in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional: Create notecards as you read OR use our notecards/app to sneak in study time while commuting or during coffee breaks at work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete all End of Chapter Questions in the CFA-I curriculum and/or third party notes. Review your answers immediately afterwards. Make a note of the page numbers for these questions and the questions you got wrong andt those that cover very important topics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following week while advancing on new material use your notes, our summary notes, or notecards to hammer the previous week’s concepts during your &lt;strong&gt;marginal study time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule-of-l1-readings-to-cover&quot;&gt;Schedule of L1 Readings to Cover&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Reading #&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Reading Titles&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Ethics &amp;amp; GIPS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1,2,3,4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ethics &amp;amp; GIPS&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Quantitative Methods&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;5, 6,7,8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Time Value of Money, Discounted Cash Flows, Statistical Concepts and Market Returns, Probability Concepts&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Quantitative Methods, Economics&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;9,10,11,12&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Common Probability Distributions, Sampling &amp;amp; Estimation, Hypothesis Testing, Technical Analysis&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;(Micro)Economics and Heavy Quant Review&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;13,14,15&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Demand &amp;amp; Supply Analysis: Introduction, Demand &amp;amp; Supply Analysis: Consumer Demand, Demand and Supply Analysis: The Firm&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;(Macro)Economics&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;17,18,19,20,21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Aggregate Output, Prices, and Economic Growth, Understanding Business Cycles, Monetary and Fiscal Policy, International Trade and Capital Flows, Currency Exchange Rates&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Financial Statement Analysis and Heavy Economics Review&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;22,23,24,25&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Financial Statement Analysis: An Introduction, Financial Reporting Mechanics, Financial Reporting Standards, Understanding Income Statements&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Financial Statement Analysis&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;26,27,28,29,30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Understanding Balance Sheets, Understanding Cash Flow Statements, Financial Analysis Techniques, Inventories, Long-lived Assets, Income Taxes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Financial Statement Analysis, Corporate Finance&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;31,32,33,34,35,36&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Income Taxes, Non-current (Long-term Liabilities), Financial Reporting Quality, Financial Statement Analysis: Applications, Capital Budgeting, Cost of Capital&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Corporate Finance, Portfolio Management&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;37,38,39,40,41&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Measures of Leverage, Dividends and Share Repurchases, Basics Working Capital Management, Corporate Governance, Portfolio Management: An Overview&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Portfolio Management&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;42, 43, 44, 45, 46&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Portfolio Risk and Return: Part I/Part II, Basics of Portfolio Planning and Construction, Market Organization and Structure, Security Market Indices&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Equity Investments&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;47,48,49,50,51&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Market Efficiency, Overview of Equity Securities, Introduction to Industry and Company Analysis, Equity Valuation: Concepts and Basic Tools, Fixed-Income Securities: Defining Elements&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Fixed-Income Securities&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;52,53,54,55,56&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Fixed-Income Markets: Issuance, Trading, and Funding, Introduction to Fixed-Income Valuation, An Introduction to Asset-Backed Securities,  Understanding Fixed-Income Risk and Return, Fundamentals of Credit Analysis&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Derivatives, Alternatives&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;57,58,59,60&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Derivative Markets and Instruments, Basics of Derivative Pricing and Valuation, Risk Management Applications of Option Strategies, Introduction to Alternative Investments&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Mock Exams&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Mock Exams&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;potential-issues-with-the-above-study-plan&quot;&gt;Potential Issues with the Above Study Plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In no particular order here are some potential modifications to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover the material faster so you have more cram time at the end. This schedule almost assumes the ability to dedicate 10-12 hours of study time per day for those last 10-14 days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skip Ethics and GIPS and save it for the end&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spend less time with Economics and FRA. The key risk in the schedule above is encountering core concepts like Equity Valuation, Fixed Income, and even Derivatives and the newly increased-in-weight Portfolio Management section relatively late in the game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With limited time you should consider reading 3rd party notes (ours are a supplement not a replacement) instead of the original CFA-I curriculum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start mock exams earlier to cover material. Even if you are unfamiliar you’ll see problems ahead of encountering the section and be primed to learn them more efficiently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/blog/three-month-schedule-to-pass-l1</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/blog/three-month-schedule-to-pass-l1</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>The 5 Most Important Takeaways from the Time Value of Money Reading</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-you-need-to-know-after-reading-the-first-chapter-of-quantitative-methods&quot;&gt;What you need to know after Reading the first chapter of Quantitative Methods&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Time Value of Money (TVM) reading kicks off Quantitative Methods. Rest assured that its placement at the beginning is not an accident. The lessons in this reading are crucially important to many of the financial calculations throughout the L1 curriculum and often are the last component of solving multiple types of calculations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post we’ll quickly break down the key takeaways that you should walk away with after reading the section and some of the core testable areas you need to be prepared for on the CFA Level 1 exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-meaning-of-interest-rates&quot;&gt;(1) The meaning of interest rates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is an interest rate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be able to explain that the interest rate can be interpreted as (a) the required rate of return, (b) the discount rate, or (3) as an opportunity cost and be able to define each of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-components-go-into-determining-the-interest-rate&quot;&gt;(2) What components go into determining the interest rate?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interest rate consists of several different risk factors (premiums) that we add up to find the overall interest rate. We usually break these different factors into the (a) risk free rate, (b) inflation, and (c) various other premiums that can include things like illiquidity and security specific factors. In this section the equation we are given is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/img/Interest-rate-components.png&quot; alt=&quot;Components of an interest rate for CFA Level 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those different risk premiums explain why the expected rate of return (&lt;em&gt;you remember that’s one way to interpret the interest rate right!?&lt;/em&gt;) varies for different asset classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, while it’s only hinted at in this reading, you will eventually also need a good understanding of the difference between the nominal and real interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compound-interest-rates-and-how-they-link-present-value-and-future-value&quot;&gt;(3) Compound interest rates and how they link Present Value, and Future Value&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of present value and future value is essential. You won’t get far in the CFA curriculum (or in finance) without understanding that money today is more valuable than money in the future. Exactly how much more valuable is determined by the compound interest rate and the amount of time that passes between now and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The equation you’ll need to memorize for the rest of your CFA life that models this relationship is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/img/FV-and-PV.png&quot; alt=&quot;Future Value, Present Value, and Compound Interest Rates&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If that equation isn’t familiar yet go read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mathsisfun.com/money/compound-interest.html&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;indexing-different-cash-flows-to-one-point-in-time&quot;&gt;(4) Indexing different cash flows to one point in time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future value/present value calculations on the exam will attempt to layer in different levels of complexity into what looks like a basic calculation in order to make a given problem more difficult than a simple formulaic plug and play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common way they do this is by requiring you to use the &lt;strong&gt;cash flow additivity principle&lt;/strong&gt; to index different future values to a single point in time where they can then be added together. To handle this be confident in using a timeline to determine different net present values and add them up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This becomes especially relevant with problems addressing annuities and annuities due. Practice those types of problems repeatedly. Why? First because they’ll be directly tested. Second, because once you have the intuition of when cash flows start and can successfully solve those present value calculations you know you’ve mastered this reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dealing-with-different-frequencies-of-compounding&quot;&gt;(5) Dealing with Different Frequencies of Compounding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should be confident taking time periods and converting them to the relevant compounding periods and doing the same with given interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So if a problem gives you the interest rate as an annual number and the time in years, but the loan whose PV you are solving for has quarterly compounding what do you do?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;You would divide r by 4 to get your quarterly interest rate (I/Y) and you would multiply the number of years by 4 to get N.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t perform that type of conversion you’ll end up inputting incorrect variables into the formula or your financial calculator and miss a lot of easy points. Plus if you can do that there’s also an entire set of equations dealing with different compounding frequencies you can ignore trying to memorize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If nothing else always remember that the &lt;strong&gt;higher&lt;/strong&gt; the interest rate or the &lt;strong&gt;more time&lt;/strong&gt; we are taking into consideration the &lt;strong&gt;higher&lt;/strong&gt; the FV of an investment will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mastering-your-financial-calculator&quot;&gt;(6) Mastering your Financial Calculator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reading is the first introduction to your financial calculator. Being able to use it across functions will let you circumvent a lot of the formulaic memorization that often plagues L1 Candidates as they grapple with hundreds of different equations. At a bare minimum you should emerge from the EOC questions in this reading being able to toggle between BGN and END and navigating NPV, IRR, and uneven cash flow problems. This will not only up your chances of actually getting specific problems right, but will let you get to other problems more quickly (&lt;em&gt;and trust us for an exam where you need to answer 1 problem every 90 seconds saving time matters a lot more than you might think&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to summarize you need to walk away from the TVM reading knowing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to interpret an interest rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What factors go into determining the interest rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Present Value and Future Value are related&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bringing multiple cash flows from the future back to today or vice versa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dealing with different compounding frequencies and manipulating the interest rate accordingly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to use that financial calculator you’ll fail without&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/blog/5-key-takeaways-from-tvm-reading</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/blog/5-key-takeaways-from-tvm-reading</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>CFA Level 1 Exam Topic Weights</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;cfa-level-1-topic-weights-explained-for-20152016&quot;&gt;CFA Level 1 Topic Weights Explained for 2015/2016&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could just have easily called this post “How the CFA L1 fits into the overall CFA Curriculum.”That’s because the first part of devising an effective study plan is understanding what you’re expected to know. Makes sense right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;level-1-topic-weights&quot;&gt;Level 1 Topic Weights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exam is broken down into ten different subject areas that cover the basic areas of investment valuation and portfolio management a financial professional is expected to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/img/Topic-areas.png&quot; alt=&quot;CFA Exam Level 1 Topic weights&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broadly speaking, these ten categories fall into four sub-categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ethics / professional standards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investment tools - Basic framework (quant/econ/international trade/currency)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coverage of individual asset classes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Portfolio / wealth management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-you-need-to-know-to-be-a-charterholder&quot;&gt;What you need to know to be a Charterholder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The L1 topic weights are obviously instructive. But its also helpful to contextualize them relative to what else you’re going to need to learn to pass all three levels to earn the Charter. Why? Because the CFA Exam makers know that they have three levels to ensure they completely test your knowledge base, and they’ll weight L1 more on areas that don’t get tested later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So how do we use this to help prepare for L1?&lt;/em&gt; by the time you’re done with the CFA curriculum you need to know (1) how to act, (2) what tools exist to evaluate investment decisions, (3) how to think about and understand all the major asset classes, and (4)how to put all of that together to help a client make the right choices for their portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the different weights across the different exams, each one tends to emphasize a part of that process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 3 is primarily about portfolio management.&lt;/strong&gt; It asks you to synthesize all the knowledge you learned in L1/L2 and apply it in a real world context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 2 goes really deep into evaluating individual asset classes.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s the most in-depth and technical when it comes to evaluating / calculating valuations for fixed income, derivatives, and equities. It also challenges Candidates by embedding problems within longer passages. So you need to know not only how to solve a problem, but what information is relevant and what information you can discard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s no surprise then that Level 1 is a broad introduction to a lot of this material.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll need a grasp of the different asset classes and you’ll be introduced to different tools and equations to examine each. But you won’t go as deep as L2 and you don’t need to put concepts together as readily as in L3. Finally, this is testing ground number one to hammer home your ethical responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breaking-down-l1s-key-sections&quot;&gt;Breaking down L1’s Key Sections&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A significant portion of the exam drills into the basic building blocks and tools you need for everything else to make sense.&lt;/strong&gt; Without getting to exhaustive, let’s go a little deeper on a few of the key areas you need to master.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethics is one of these fundamental blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a HUGE component of L1. Yet despite the 15% weighting, many Candidates understimate the section. You see, Ethics questions appear deceptively simple when they actually take a lot of getting used to. You’ll have approximately 36 problems dealing with Ethics. Do plenty of practice problems. Not convinced yet? &lt;strong&gt;In the event you are on the border of pass and fail, your score in Ethics is  used to determine if you should move to Level 2.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quantitative Methods and Economics are also heavily stressed in L1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need a strong grounding in probability and statistics (including regression analysis) to score well in the quantative methods section. Economics can also be quite challenging if you don’t have an academic background in it. This section is often really tedious. It has de-railed many good intentions. If you need to, skim this during your first pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Financial Reporting and Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the largest section of L1 and it’s also one of the most challenging for most Candidates. Not only that, everything you learn here is vital to getting through L2 as well. Note that Financial reporting has a real mix of both conceptual material and calcuation and ratio heavy material that makes it a lengthy section. There’s no alternative but to grind through this material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this high level overview of it’s worth reading about the exam format itself (if you’re not already familiar). We’ll post about that next week.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/blog/topic-weights</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/blog/topic-weights</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Getting Started</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-hardest-part-of-level-1-is-getting-started&quot;&gt;The Hardest part of Level 1 is getting started&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest things to do in the entire CFA process is to start studying for level one. There’s a lot of material to cover and life is busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, despite our best intentions, it often happens that we find days slipping by without covering any material. &lt;em&gt;I’ll just read a little extra tomorrow you say to yourself.&lt;/em&gt; And it is true, a few days here and there is OK (in fact, we’ve long advocated planned zero days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;zero-days-compound&quot;&gt;Zero Days Compound&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But putting together multiple zero days has a compounding effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You get used to not working or covering material.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you do study you try to cram lots of material at once (which is sub-optimal for retention)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perhaps even worse, you start feeling a nervous tension that builds up because you know you’re not doing what you need to prepare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result is that you’re not studying and you’re also not enjoying your free time because you feel like you should be. The CFA study process is hard enough without becoming your own worst enemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cfa-is-a-grind&quot;&gt;The CFA Is a Grind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passing Level 1 (and then 2 and 3) depends on grinding the material over time. Little habits really do add up. And while everyone will find their own groove, we’ve been around the block (both ourselves and with hundreds of other Candidates) and we’ve distilled out a few lessons from that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;know-the-basic-outline-of-the-material-and-the-ways-it-is-interlinked&quot;&gt;Know the basic outline of the material and the ways it is interlinked&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you dive into the weeds you need the thousand foot view. You need to have a general idea of the topics you’re going to be expected to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do various topics link together and build on one another?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What areas are more conceptual and which are calculation heavy?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What percentage of the exam points are assigned to each topic?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing how topics relate to one another helps you chunk material and streamlines your memorization (and it’s one of the specialties of our notes). Knowing the topic weights lets you spend your time on the highest leverage topics. That way if you are weak on an area that might only show up in 1-2 questions you can skip it, but if you struggle with fixed income you know you need to drill problems in that area repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;understand-the-perspective-of-the-test-makers&quot;&gt;Understand the perspective of the test makers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of reasons to undertake the CFA Exam. But we’re willing to bet that your number one goal is to PASS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who cares if you’ve memorized every detail. There’s no grade here. You need to score 70% on three exams. Period. To do that, it’s helpful to understand what the CFA Institute is asking you to learn for each level, why they might be driving towards that, and how they format the exam to meet their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;find-your-cadence--steal-study-time&quot;&gt;Find your Cadence &amp;amp; Steal Study Time&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Level 1 is often considered the easiest of the CFA exams it comes with an extra wrinkle. Everything is new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You haven’t learned the style of the material and the way it is presented. You haven’t done enough practice problems yet to know how this material can be tested. You don’t know exactly what it takes to pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s OK. You’ll adapt. We’ll provide you a framework for all of it. Before too long you’ll see that the material has a certain cadence to it. It gets easier the more you do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust us when we say that incremental marginal improvements can really add up. Your job is to find the right routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;figure-out-how-to-hack-the-test&quot;&gt;Figure out how to Hack the Test&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you study you’ll get more comfortable with the various topics, your areas of strength and weakness, and the variations of how problems can get tested and how the test takers might try to trick you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That entire process takes time and effort. We like to think that we can help you hack that process by pointing out areas of emphasis, the ways problems have been asked in the past, and the key tricks and tips that will help save you hours and hours of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we encode that knowledge in a variety of study tools–notes, a study app, and our newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;one-way-to-get-started-is-with-our-free-newsletter&quot;&gt;One way to get started is with our free newsletter&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re here to help and we’re dedicated to that task. That’s why we have a free CFA newsletter that we stuff with everything we know about how to hack the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;a href=&quot;http://cfaexamlevel1.com/newsletter/&quot;&gt;sign up&lt;/a&gt; for it you’ll get &lt;strong&gt;access to hundreds of pages of our study material&lt;/strong&gt; for free and exclusive access to the beta of our app. We’re here to answer your questions and point you in the right direction using everything we’ve learned passing the test ourselves and helping countless others to do so ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So sign up for our newsletter and we’ll send you a first review chapter to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/blog/getting%20started</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/blog/getting started</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>There are no shortcuts</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;there-are-no-shortcuts-to-the-cfa-exam&quot;&gt;There are no shortcuts to the CFA Exam&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of the CFA Level 1 process may just be getting started. It’s also the most important part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CFA material is long (2,500+ pages for level 1 alone). It is detailed. It will take time to learn the material, understand the types of problems you’ll need to know how to answer, and then practice over and over until you get comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s true even if you’ve worked in finance for 30 years. There are no real shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gospel is that the average Candidate needs to study 300 hours to pass the test. It could be more or less for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our job here at &lt;a href=&quot;www.cfaexamlevel1.com&quot;&gt;Go Study&lt;/a&gt; is to make sure you learn everything you need to pass the test while minimizing that time commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all about quality and efficiency here (&lt;a href=&quot;www.cfaexamlevel3.com&quot;&gt;just ask the 500+ level 3 Candidates we just helped)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, efficiency has limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-just-start-start-mentally-prepared&quot;&gt;Don’t just start, start mentally prepared&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passing all three Level 3 exams is a daunting challenge, and for your own sake you should be mentally prepared for that grind before you start Level 1. There are no prizes for being stuck as a CFA Level II Candidate.  You will make sacrifices with your time, there will be &lt;em&gt;opportunity costs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It will take years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still interested?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CFA curriculum will teach you something new. Its community is powerful, its designation recognized throughout the world. It can help open doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-will-help-you-walk-the-path&quot;&gt;We will help you walk the path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know the pain of passing these tests. We’ve been where you are.  We are here to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first step with us should be to register for our &lt;a href=&quot;http://cfaexamlevel1.com/newsletter/&quot;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. It’s completely free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just like we did with level 3, we’ll use our newsletter to release  hundreds of pages of our Level 1 notes to you for free as well as sharing tips, tricks, additional study resources, walk throughs of difficult problems, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/blog/there-are-no-shortcuts</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/blog/there-are-no-shortcuts</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
